<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Labs on BIO 108 and 217</title>
    <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/labs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Labs on BIO 108 and 217</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 13:12:21 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/labs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>May 10 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/labs/may-10-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 13:12:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/labs/may-10-lab/</guid>
      <description>The three students enrolled in BIO 217 have class on May 10 and have decided to go on a trip. Students in BIO 108 do not have class and instead have Snow/Study Day. However, 108 students are welcome to join the trip; ideally, let me know if you&amp;rsquo;re coming.
Plan We&amp;rsquo;ll go to Alley Pond Park in Queens. We&amp;rsquo;ll park at the parking lot with access from Wincester Blvd. (What3Words location error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May 3 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/labs/may-03-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 17:01:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/labs/may-03-lab/</guid>
      <description>Plan We&amp;rsquo;re planning to go to Jamaica Bay Wildlife Refuge (eBird hotspot) for an extended trip, leaving at 8 from the regular place and returning about 12:30. See the illustrated checklist for an idea about what&amp;rsquo;s possible there for the first week of May. Songbirds are towards the bottom of that list. It should be awesome.
We will park at and start from the Visitor&amp;rsquo;s Center, where we may need to fill out permits for you if it is open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apr 26 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/labs/apr-26-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 11:46:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/labs/apr-26-lab/</guid>
      <description>Plan The van is back for real (they say!), and the birds are at Hempstead Lake SP (hotspot - South End, illustrated histogram.
Target species: Swallows (Barn, Bank, Tree, and keeping an eye out for Northern Rough-winged and Cliff) and Chimney Swift from last week&amp;rsquo;s learning group, Sparrows we haven&amp;rsquo;t observed (Savannah, Swamp, Eastern Towhee), and especially a large number of arriving songbirds at the front-end of their frequency pulse (warblers, vireos, orioles, Indigo Bunting, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apr 19 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/labs/apr-19-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 21:53:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/labs/apr-19-lab/</guid>
      <description>Plan We were heading to Valley Stream SP, but there wasn&amp;rsquo;t a van, so we walked around campus.
Expected conditions nice
Jobs I did the recording.
eBird list On campus: Hofstra University</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>