<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>classes on BIO 108 and 217</title>
    <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/tags/classes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in classes on BIO 108 and 217</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 11:16:18 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/tags/classes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 08 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-08-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 11:16:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-08-class/</guid>
      <description>We began with a bit of history, noting the emergence of field-recognition techniques and contrast between the “field marks” and GISS or BBI approaches. Then we focused how to pay attention to and talk about size, shape, and structure, including relative size and proportions.
Learning species (for quiz next week) These were the species for which we carefully examined differences.
 Downy Woodpecker Hairy Woodpecker Common Loon Red-throated Loon  Also on the quiz Shown an image of a perched bird: “Make a short list of at least four structural features of this bird that might be helpful in identifying it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 01 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-01-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 13:22:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-01-class/</guid>
      <description>(This page is under development)
-- We will meet in our Friday classroom, which is different from both your Monday classroom and our Friday lab space. It is 103 Brower (campus map location).
Learning species (for quiz next week)  American Robin Northern Mockingbird  Also, learn the vocabulary terms on the distributed sheet, to be able to recognize where they go on a picture of a bird. You can use the bird topography diagrams in your Sibley book to study this (and you can find alternative diagrams online).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class Information</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/class-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 14:32:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/class-information/</guid>
      <description>Our Friday classes will be at 11:15–12:40 in 103 Brower (campus map location).
Usual timeline Our 85-minute class sessions will normally be structured like this:
 quiz (up to 15 minutes) an identification topic (about 25 minutes) learning identifications (about 40 minutes)  Quiz Each week we will have an identification quiz at the beginning of class. The quiz will consist of ten identifications. Most of the identifications will be species (or other taxa) learned the previous week.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>