<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>classes on BIO 108 and 217</title>
    <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/tags/classes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in classes on BIO 108 and 217</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 14:56:25 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/tags/classes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apr 5 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/apr-5-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 14:56:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/apr-5-class/</guid>
      <description>Learning species (for quiz next week)  Red-winged Blackbird Brown-headed Cowbird Common Grackle American Crow Blue Jay Great Blue Heron  See also  Coincidentally, Kaeli Swift—the crow-researcher I mentioned in class as starting #croworno—talked about crow social behavior and social intelligence, including their ability to recognize humans and their attention to the deaths of group members, on this week&amp;rsquo;s American Birding Association podcast. “Are crows the ultimate problem solvers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mar 29 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-29-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 12:50:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-29-class/</guid>
      <description>Note that the quiz at the beginning of the class will cover the five new species from the March 15 class.
Learning species (for quiz next week)  White-breasted Nuthatch, Brown Creeper Carolina Wren House Wren Gray Catbird Brown Thrasher European Starling  See also  Birdcast has posted its first … birdcast for Spring 2019 migration. They do amazing work integrating weather forecasts with radar data on actual bird movements and on-the-ground observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mar 15 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-15-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 10:33:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-15-class/</guid>
      <description> The first half of the class time will be the midterm/first test. See the midterm test page. After the test, we&amp;rsquo;ll have time to learn a few more species, starting with the three we didn&amp;rsquo;t finish last time.
Learning species (for quiz next week) Falcons in Falconidae:
 American Kestrel Merlin Peregrine Falcon  Tits in Paridae
 Black-capped Chickadee Tufted Titmouse White-breasted Nuthatch  See also  A Guide for Hawks Seen in the Northeast by NorthEast Hawk Watch Eastern Migrant Raptor Flight Guide by HMANA  Afternotes </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mar 08 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-08-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 16:10:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-08-class/</guid>
      <description> Dimensions Ethics &amp;amp; safety
Learning species (for quiz next week) Diurnal raptors: Accipitridae, Falconidae, and our one species in Pandionidae.
 Osprey (Pandionidae)  Sharp-shinned Hawk (Accipitridae) Cooper’s Hawk (Accipitridae) Red-tailed Hawk (Accipitridae) Red-shouldered Hawk (Accipitridae)  (falcons delayed until next week)
See also  A Guide for Hawks Seen in the Northeast by NorthEast Hawk Watch Eastern Migrant Raptor Flight Guide by HMANA  Afternotes  American Birding Association Code of Birding Ethics  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mar 01 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-01-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 10:03:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-01-class/</guid>
      <description> Dimensions of identification Feathers, wings, and molt
Learning species (for quiz next week) We&amp;rsquo;re continuing finish waterbirds with grebes and cormorants, and starting diurnal raptors—Accipitridae hawks and other families. Required species for this week are:
 Pied-billed Grebe (Podicipedidae) Horned Grebe (Podicipedidae) Double-crested Cormorant (Phalacrocoracidae) American Coot (Rallidae)  See also (it turns out these are more relevant to next week)
 A Guide for Hawks Seen in the Northeast by NorthEast Hawk Watch Eastern Migrant Raptor Flight Guide by HMANA  Afternotes </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 22 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-22-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 15:07:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-22-class/</guid>
      <description> Dimensions of identification Flight styles. We&amp;rsquo;ll note and name a variety of them.
Learning species (for quiz next week) We&amp;rsquo;re continuing to sample waterfowl, ducks and beyond:
 Bufflehead Ruddy Duck Ring-necked Duck Greater Scaup Hooded Merganser Red-breasted Merganser Long-tailed Duck  See also  The Where&amp;rsquo;s the white? method (and sample image) of identifying (at least male and sometimes non-male) ducks.  Afternotes </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 15 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-15-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 11:18:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-15-class/</guid>
      <description>Dimensions of identification Holistic structure—flight
Learning species (for quiz next week) We&amp;rsquo;re learning dabbling ducks and diving ducks from Anatidae.
 Mallard American Black Duck Gadwall American Wigeon Northern Shoveler Wood Duck Bufflehead (will cover these last two next week) Ruddy Duck  See also  A quiz on dabbling ducks USFWS short videos on identifying ducks by their wings: Mallards, Dabbling Ducks, Diving Ducks Baby Wood Ducks leave their nest, a Nature video—the amazingness starts at about 1:35  Afternotes  The Where&amp;rsquo;s the white?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 08 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-08-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 11:16:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-08-class/</guid>
      <description>We began with a bit of history, noting the emergence of field-recognition techniques and contrast between the “field marks” and GISS or BBI approaches. Then we focused how to pay attention to and talk about size, shape, and structure, including relative size and proportions.
Learning species (for quiz next week) These were the species for which we carefully examined differences.
 Downy Woodpecker Hairy Woodpecker Common Loon Red-throated Loon  Also on the quiz Shown an image of a perched bird: “Make a short list of at least four structural features of this bird that might be helpful in identifying it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 01 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-01-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 13:22:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-01-class/</guid>
      <description>(This page is under development)
-- We will meet in our Friday classroom, which is different from both your Monday classroom and our Friday lab space. It is 103 Brower (campus map location).
Learning species (for quiz next week)  American Robin Northern Mockingbird  Also, learn the vocabulary terms on the distributed sheet, to be able to recognize where they go on a picture of a bird. You can use the bird topography diagrams in your Sibley book to study this (and you can find alternative diagrams online).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class Information</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/class-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 14:32:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/class-information/</guid>
      <description>Our Friday classes will be at 11:15–12:40 in 103 Brower (campus map location).
Usual timeline Our 85-minute class sessions will normally be structured like this:
 quiz (up to 15 minutes) an identification topic (about 25 minutes) learning identifications (about 40 minutes)  Quiz Each week we will have an identification quiz at the beginning of class. The quiz will consist of ten identifications. Most of the identifications will be species (or other taxa) learned the previous week.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>