<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on BIO 108 and 217</title>
    <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on BIO 108 and 217</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 11:47:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jamaica Bay Poll</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/jamaica-bay-poll/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 11:47:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/jamaica-bay-poll/</guid>
      <description>Hi, Please, by Thursday (Apr 25) answer the one-question poll about possibly going to Jamaica Bay Wildlife Refuge.
Additional info:
 NYC Audubon&amp;rsquo;s description of birding at the refuge; eBird hospot page for Jamaica Bay Wildlife Refuge; also, the illustrated checklist Google Maps link for Jamaica Bay Wildlife Refuge Visitor Center, where the parking lot is (175-10 Cross Bay Blvd, Broad Channel, NY 11693).  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apr 12 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/apr-12-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 11:47:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/apr-12-class/</guid>
      <description>Learning species (for quiz next week)  Great Egret Snowy Egret Yellow-crowned Night-Heron Black-crowned Night-Heron Glossy Ibis Northern Saw-whet Owl Eastern Screech-Owl  See also  I&amp;rsquo;m liking young NYC birder Jason Ward&amp;rsquo;s new YouTube series Birds of North America: “Jason Ward has been an avid birdwatcher since he was a kid growing up in the Bronx, where he spotted a peregrine falcon eating a pigeon on a ledge outside his bedroom window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apr 12 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/apr-12-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 20:33:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/apr-12-lab/</guid>
      <description>Birdcast anticipates some low-moderate migration into the area, though (as of 9 PM Thursday) their live radar is currently showing limited little movement into New Jersey and New York so far.
Plan As of Thursday evening, it is again uncertain whether we have the van to go out tomorrow. The Biology Department emailed me on Thursday afternoon, “Just a heads up that the van had some warning lights come on and [a professor] called Public Safety to take it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apr 5 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/apr-5-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 14:56:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/apr-5-class/</guid>
      <description>Learning species (for quiz next week)  Red-winged Blackbird Brown-headed Cowbird Common Grackle American Crow Blue Jay Great Blue Heron  See also  Coincidentally, Kaeli Swift—the crow-researcher I mentioned in class as starting #croworno—talked about crow social behavior and social intelligence, including their ability to recognize humans and their attention to the deaths of group members, on this week&amp;rsquo;s American Birding Association podcast. “Are crows the ultimate problem solvers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apr 5 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/apr-5-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 05:46:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/apr-5-lab/</guid>
      <description>Among the early migrants, we&amp;rsquo;ll look for arriving Night Herons, Great and Snowy Egrets, and Greater Yellowlegs. We&amp;rsquo;ll also look for a Monk Parakeet colony, and think about their ecology and history. We&amp;rsquo;ll keep an eye out for other recent arrivals, like Osprey and Killdeer and ducks moving through, like Green-winged Teal.
Plan  Cow Meadow Park and Preserve Baldwin Park Possibly Oceanside Marine Nature Study Area  Expected conditions It&amp;rsquo;s going to be colder!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mar 29 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-29-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 12:50:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-29-class/</guid>
      <description>Note that the quiz at the beginning of the class will cover the five new species from the March 15 class.
Learning species (for quiz next week)  White-breasted Nuthatch, Brown Creeper Carolina Wren House Wren Gray Catbird Brown Thrasher European Starling  See also  Birdcast has posted its first … birdcast for Spring 2019 migration. They do amazing work integrating weather forecasts with radar data on actual bird movements and on-the-ground observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mar 29 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-29-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 12:50:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-29-lab/</guid>
      <description>Plan As of now, our van is in the shop, with its brakes being repaired. We do not know whether it will be available Friday morning. If it&amp;rsquo;s not, we will work on identifying birds on campus, walking through the Pinetum over to the Bird Sanctuary and around north campus. That&amp;rsquo;ll build our familiarity with the common perching birds we are learning in class.
I&amp;rsquo;ll update here if the van becomes available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midterm Test</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/midterm-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 10:46:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/midterm-test/</guid>
      <description>The midterm test on March 15 has four parts.
Parts of the test The first part will ask you to label the names of parts of birds. The parts you may need to use are listed below. You may be given images (drawn or photographed) of a Passerine/perching bird (like on page xvi) or a duck or a hawk. Those are the groups we&amp;rsquo;ve spent time looking at. The birds in the images may be perched or in flight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mar 15 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-15-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 10:33:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-15-class/</guid>
      <description> The first half of the class time will be the midterm/first test. See the midterm test page. After the test, we&amp;rsquo;ll have time to learn a few more species, starting with the three we didn&amp;rsquo;t finish last time.
Learning species (for quiz next week) Falcons in Falconidae:
 American Kestrel Merlin Peregrine Falcon  Tits in Paridae
 Black-capped Chickadee Tufted Titmouse White-breasted Nuthatch  See also  A Guide for Hawks Seen in the Northeast by NorthEast Hawk Watch Eastern Migrant Raptor Flight Guide by HMANA  Afternotes </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mar 15 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-15-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 10:33:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-15-lab/</guid>
      <description>Plan We&amp;rsquo;ll walk around nearby Eisenhower Park and probably Hempstead Plains Preserve. As of Thursday, thunderstorms are 50% likely for class time, so the plan will be to be able to retreat to the van if any significant rain or storm arrives.
Expected conditions Warm, but possibly rainy. Maybe put a raincoat on as your outer layer, and/or toss an umbrella in your bag.
Jobs Following the recorder rotation, Trevor is recording with Nick assisting Nick recorded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mar 08 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-08-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 16:10:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-08-class/</guid>
      <description> Dimensions Ethics &amp;amp; safety
Learning species (for quiz next week) Diurnal raptors: Accipitridae, Falconidae, and our one species in Pandionidae.
 Osprey (Pandionidae)  Sharp-shinned Hawk (Accipitridae) Cooper’s Hawk (Accipitridae) Red-tailed Hawk (Accipitridae) Red-shouldered Hawk (Accipitridae)  (falcons delayed until next week)
See also  A Guide for Hawks Seen in the Northeast by NorthEast Hawk Watch Eastern Migrant Raptor Flight Guide by HMANA  Afternotes  American Birding Association Code of Birding Ethics  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mar 08 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-08-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 16:10:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-08-lab/</guid>
      <description>Plan We&amp;rsquo;ll go to Valley Stream State Park. Our focus will continue to be on waterfowl and possible raptors, but also we&amp;rsquo;ll begin spending increasing time looking for perching birds in woods and edge habitats. In addition, we&amp;rsquo;ll try to walk the mile down to Arthur Hendrickson Park to see if the Cackling Goose that has been hanging around there with the Canada Geese flock is around.
Expected conditions It&amp;rsquo;s still going to be cold, so please continue layering up, but we will be in a less-exposed, non-coastal place, partly in the woods, and mostly on pavement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mar 01 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-01-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 10:03:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-01-class/</guid>
      <description> Dimensions of identification Feathers, wings, and molt
Learning species (for quiz next week) We&amp;rsquo;re continuing finish waterbirds with grebes and cormorants, and starting diurnal raptors—Accipitridae hawks and other families. Required species for this week are:
 Pied-billed Grebe (Podicipedidae) Horned Grebe (Podicipedidae) Double-crested Cormorant (Phalacrocoracidae) American Coot (Rallidae)  See also (it turns out these are more relevant to next week)
 A Guide for Hawks Seen in the Northeast by NorthEast Hawk Watch Eastern Migrant Raptor Flight Guide by HMANA  Afternotes </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mar 01 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-01-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 10:03:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-01-lab/</guid>
      <description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the Field Trip Instructions and Weekly Checklist Assignment pages yet, please do!
Plan We&amp;rsquo;ll deploy our diving-duck and related waterfowl skills and keep an eye out for winter perching birds and hawks. New hawks for us would include Cooper&amp;rsquo;s Hawk, Sharp-shinned Hawk, and Northern Harrier. We&amp;rsquo;ll start by scanning Jones Bay from the Jones Beach Coast Guard Station. Horned Grebes often peak about now, for instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 22 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-22-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 15:07:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-22-class/</guid>
      <description> Dimensions of identification Flight styles. We&amp;rsquo;ll note and name a variety of them.
Learning species (for quiz next week) We&amp;rsquo;re continuing to sample waterfowl, ducks and beyond:
 Bufflehead Ruddy Duck Ring-necked Duck Greater Scaup Hooded Merganser Red-breasted Merganser Long-tailed Duck  See also  The Where&amp;rsquo;s the white? method (and sample image) of identifying (at least male and sometimes non-male) ducks.  Afternotes </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 22 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-22-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 15:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-22-lab/</guid>
      <description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the Field Trip Instructions page yet, please do!
Plan We&amp;rsquo;re going to focus on using our accumulating waterfowl skills on five varying freshwater bodies around Hempstead Lake State Park.
 We&amp;rsquo;ll plan to start at Smith Pond, a ten-minute drive south of HLSP. We&amp;rsquo;ll scan the pond from the parking lot of Morgan Days Park (What3Words location: vibe.birds.rift; lat/long: 40.659928, -73.653044). ebird hotspot: https://ebird.org/hotspot/L444839. Then we&amp;rsquo;ll move promptly to the state park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 15 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-15-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 11:18:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-15-class/</guid>
      <description>Dimensions of identification Holistic structure—flight
Learning species (for quiz next week) We&amp;rsquo;re learning dabbling ducks and diving ducks from Anatidae.
 Mallard American Black Duck Gadwall American Wigeon Northern Shoveler Wood Duck Bufflehead (will cover these last two next week) Ruddy Duck  See also  A quiz on dabbling ducks USFWS short videos on identifying ducks by their wings: Mallards, Dabbling Ducks, Diving Ducks Baby Wood Ducks leave their nest, a Nature video—the amazingness starts at about 1:35  Afternotes  The Where&amp;rsquo;s the white?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 15 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-15-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 11:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-15-lab/</guid>
      <description>Update: the van is apparently repaired, so we&amp;rsquo;re planning to use it. But if anyone prefers to travel to the first site on your own—Google Maps locations are below—and meet us there without coming to Hofstra, please contact me about that.
Plan  Oyster Bay Marine Center (Sagamore Yacht Club); target species: bay waterfowl, especially the rare in New York Pacific Loon that has been there for almost two weeks, but also Bufflehead, mergansers, scaup, gulls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learned Species</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/learned-species/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 12:35:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/learned-species/</guid>
      <description>This is a running list of the species we have learned in class so far, and which may therefore appear on quizzes, midterm, and/or final:
 American Robin Northern Mockingbird Downy Woodpecker Hairy Woodpecker Common Loon Red-throated Loon Mallard American Black Duck Gadwall American Wigeon Northern Shoveler Wood Duck Bufflehead Ruddy Duck Ring-necked Duck Greater Scaup Hooded Merganser Red-breasted Merganser Long-tailed Duck Pied-billed Grebe Horned Grebe Double-crested Cormorant American Coot Osprey Sharp-shinned Hawk Cooper’s Hawk Red-tailed Hawk Red-shouldered Hawk American Kestrel Merlin Peregrine Falcon Black-capped Chickadee Tufted Titmouse White-breasted Nuthatch Brown Creeper Carolina Wren House Wren Gray Catbird Brown Thrasher European Starling Red-winged Blackbird Brown-headed Cowbird Common Grackle American Crow Blue Jay Great Blue Heron Great Egret Snowy Egret Yellow-crowned Night-Heron Black-crowned Night-Heron Glossy Ibis Northern Saw-whet Owl Eastern Screech-Owl Ruby-throated Hummingbird Tree Swallow Barn Swallow Purple Martin Chimney Swift Eastern Wood-Pewee House Finch Scarlet Tanager Red-eyed Vireo Yellow-rumped Warbler American Redstart Common Yellowthroat Yellow Warbler  last updated April 26, 2019</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Checklist Note Assignment</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/weekly-checklist-note-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 10:01:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/weekly-checklist-note-assignment/</guid>
      <description>Each week after lab, unless you are the week&amp;rsquo;s recorder or deputy, your assignment is to post a note on the group checklist (or one of the group&amp;rsquo;s checklists; sometimes there will be more than one). This is due within a week, before the next lab.
Set up (you only need to do this once) Create an eBird account as soon as you can after our first lab. Go to the eBird main page at https://ebird.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 08 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-08-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 11:16:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-08-lab/</guid>
      <description>Remember to bring your completed Field Trip Waiver form. You will need it to attend the lab.
Please sign up for an eBird account soon (see Using eBird), so we can share the lab checklist with you.
Plan We will go to the west end of Jones Beach State Park. Our planned first stop will be for a walk through the dunes and beach at Jones Beach SP&amp;ndash;West End, looking at the dunes, the beach, the ocean, and Jones Inlet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 08 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-08-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 11:16:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-08-class/</guid>
      <description>We began with a bit of history, noting the emergence of field-recognition techniques and contrast between the “field marks” and GISS or BBI approaches. Then we focused how to pay attention to and talk about size, shape, and structure, including relative size and proportions.
Learning species (for quiz next week) These were the species for which we carefully examined differences.
 Downy Woodpecker Hairy Woodpecker Common Loon Red-throated Loon  Also on the quiz Shown an image of a perched bird: “Make a short list of at least four structural features of this bird that might be helpful in identifying it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recorder Rotation</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/recorder-rotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 12:17:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/recorder-rotation/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the planned rotation for lab recorders and deputies (see Field Trip Instructions for an explanation and instructions):
   Sequence Recorder Deputy Date     1 Penelope Selina Feb 8   2 Wayne Safiyah Feb 15   3 Nick Sean Feb 22   4 Haley Penelope Mar 1   5 Anthony Wayne Mar 8   6 Trevor Nick Mar 15   7 Chris Haley Mar 29   8 Alex Anthony Apr 5   9 Selina Trevor Apr 12   10 Safiyah Chris Apr 26   11 Sean Alex TBD    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 01 Class</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-01-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 13:22:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-01-class/</guid>
      <description>(This page is under development)
-- We will meet in our Friday classroom, which is different from both your Monday classroom and our Friday lab space. It is 103 Brower (campus map location).
Learning species (for quiz next week)  American Robin Northern Mockingbird  Also, learn the vocabulary terms on the distributed sheet, to be able to recognize where they go on a picture of a bird. You can use the bird topography diagrams in your Sibley book to study this (and you can find alternative diagrams online).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 01 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-01-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 13:20:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-01-lab/</guid>
      <description>Plan Introductory presentation in our lab space, Gittleson 323. Then, outdoor walk around Hofstra campus to look for birds for up to 90 minutes. (Not going outside. Severe cold warnings.  )
Special instructions If you have binoculars, please bring them. (If not, no problem.) Dress just to be outside at Hofstra, but warmly because it we will plan to be out for up to 90 minutes, and not always walking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using eBird</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/using-ebird/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 13:15:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/using-ebird/</guid>
      <description>What is eBird?  eBird is the world’s largest biodiversity-related citizen science project, with more than 100 million bird sightings contributed each year by eBirders around the world. A collaborative enterprise with hundreds of partner organizations, thousands of regional experts, and hundreds of thousands of users, eBird is managed by the Cornell Lab of Ornithology. […] eBird data are … freely accessible to anyone. eBird data have been used in hundreds of conservation decisions and peer-reviewed papers, and [in] thousands of student projects; and [they] help inform bird research worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Identification Resources</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/online-identification-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 15:40:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/online-identification-resources/</guid>
      <description>([Eliot](http://people.hofstra.edu/Christopher_H_Eliot/home.html), BIO 108/217, Spring 2015) -- These are resources I think are useful for general/visual bird identification. You might find them helpful either for this class or for your continued learning and field-work.
Free field guides  All About Birds at Cornell includes accurate information and reliably-identified photos of birds at various ages and plumage-types. National Audubon Society&amp;rsquo;s Guide to North American Birds is another good online guide with both photos and drawings by David Sibley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommended Books</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/recommended-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 10:40:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/recommended-books/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s quite recent that some excellent bird-identification materials have moved online. Ten years ago there was approximately nothing. Now there are some very good ones. Still, much of the best and most useful information is available only in books. You won&amp;rsquo;t need these for the course, but you may want to learn more than what we cover in the course.
So, besides your Big Sibley, some of the books I value most are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Independent Observation Assignment</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/independent-observation-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 14:33:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/independent-observation-assignment/</guid>
      <description>Task Observe birds independently for a cumulative 80 minutes minimum, and submit an eBird checklist (or checklists) documenting what you found.
Due Email links to your checklist(s) to me by Monday May 13.
Instructions Sometime during the semester, or several times, you should observe and count birds on your own outside of class for a combined minimum of 80 minutes. It can be one continuous count, or as many as eight different times and places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class Information</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/class-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 14:32:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/class-information/</guid>
      <description>Our Friday classes will be at 11:15–12:40 in 103 Brower (campus map location).
Usual timeline Our 85-minute class sessions will normally be structured like this:
 quiz (up to 15 minutes) an identification topic (about 25 minutes) learning identifications (about 40 minutes)  Quiz Each week we will have an identification quiz at the beginning of class. The quiz will consist of ten identifications. Most of the identifications will be species (or other taxa) learned the previous week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Field Trip Instructions</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/field-trip-instructions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 14:32:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/field-trip-instructions/</guid>
      <description>We will go on a field trip nearly every Friday morning at 8. Usually we will ride in the van to one or two destinations less than 30 minutes from Hofstra. We will normally return by 11 AM. Very occasionally, we might cut into class time, which immediately follows.
Preparations in advance  We will need your signed/filled-in permission form before you can go on any trips off campus. Seriously, plan to be able to dress—just a few times—for very cold conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optional Materials</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/optional-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 16:00:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/optional-materials/</guid>
      <description>The following are not in any way required. Just, you might value these things if you have them available:
Sunglasses If you have sunglasses that you can see well through, they can help keep your eyes relaxed and happy while staring into bright and variable light, sometimes in the wind. And your eyes are your main tool for labs.
Microfiber cloth Especially if you wear glasses, but also for your binoculars, being able to wipe off smudges can noticeably improve your experience of watching things carefully outdoors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Required Materials</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/required-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 15:00:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/required-materials/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s what you will need for the course:
Book The identification guide you need for this course is: The Sibley Guide to Birds, 2nd edition (2014), by David Allen Sibley, published Alfred A. Knopf. ISBN: 9780307957900 (Worldcat) .
You may want to bring the book to class; it&amp;rsquo;s optional. You do not need to bring the book to labs.
Binoculars (yours or ours) If you already have binoculars or can borrow some from someone for the duration of the course, they will be useful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>