<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>labs on BIO 108 and 217</title>
    <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/tags/labs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in labs on BIO 108 and 217</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 10:01:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/tags/labs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Checklist Note Assignment</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/weekly-checklist-note-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 10:01:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/weekly-checklist-note-assignment/</guid>
      <description>Each week after lab, unless you are the week&amp;rsquo;s recorder or deputy, your assignment is to post a note on the group checklist (or one of the group&amp;rsquo;s checklists; sometimes there will be more than one). This is due within a week, before the next lab.
Set up (you only need to do this once) Create an eBird account as soon as you can after our first lab. Go to the eBird main page at https://ebird.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 08 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-08-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 11:16:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-08-lab/</guid>
      <description>Remember to bring your completed Field Trip Waiver form. You will need it to attend the lab.
Please sign up for an eBird account soon (see Using eBird), so we can share the lab checklist with you.
Plan We will go to the west end of Jones Beach State Park. Our planned first stop will be for a walk through the dunes and beach at Jones Beach SP&amp;ndash;West End, looking at the dunes, the beach, the ocean, and Jones Inlet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recorder Rotation</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/recorder-rotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 12:17:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/recorder-rotation/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the planned rotation for lab recorders and deputies (see Field Trip Instructions for an explanation and instructions):
   Sequence Recorder Deputy Actual Date     1 Penelope Selina Feb 8   2 Wayne Safiyah TBD   3 Nick Sean TBD   4 TBD TBD TBD    (more rows to come!)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 01 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-01-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 13:20:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-01-lab/</guid>
      <description>Plan Introductory presentation in our lab space, Gittleson 323. Then, outdoor walk around Hofstra campus to look for birds for up to 90 minutes. (Not going outside. Severe cold warnings.  )
Special instructions If you have binoculars, please bring them. (If not, no problem.) Dress just to be outside at Hofstra, but warmly because it we will plan to be out for up to 90 minutes, and not always walking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Field Trip Instructions</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/field-trip-instructions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 14:32:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/field-trip-instructions/</guid>
      <description>We will go on a field trip nearly every Friday morning at 8. Usually we will ride in the van to one or two destinations less than 30 minutes from Hofstra. We will normally return by 11 AM. Very occasionally, we might cut into class time, which immediately follows.
Preparations in advance  We will need your signed/filled-in permission form before you can go on any trips off campus. Seriously, plan to be able to dress—just a few times—for very cold conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>