<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>labs on BIO 108 and 217</title>
    <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/tags/labs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in labs on BIO 108 and 217</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 05:46:17 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/tags/labs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Apr 5</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/lab-apr-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 05:46:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/lab-apr-5/</guid>
      <description>Among the early migrants, we&amp;rsquo;ll look for arriving Night Herons, Great and Snowy Egrets, and Greater Yellowlegs. We&amp;rsquo;ll also look for a Monk Parakeet colony, and think about their ecology and history. We&amp;rsquo;ll keep an eye out for other recent arrivals, like Osprey and Killdeer and ducks moving through, like Green-winged Teal.
Plan  Cow Meadow Park and Preserve Baldwin Park Possibly Oceanside Marine Nature Study Area  Expected conditions It&amp;rsquo;s going to be colder!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mar 29 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-29-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 12:50:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-29-lab/</guid>
      <description>Plan As of now, our van is in the shop, with its brakes being repaired. We do not know whether it will be available Friday morning. If it&amp;rsquo;s not, we will work on identifying birds on campus, walking through the Pinetum over to the Bird Sanctuary and around north campus. That&amp;rsquo;ll build our familiarity with the common perching birds we are learning in class.
I&amp;rsquo;ll update here if the van becomes available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mar 15 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-15-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 10:33:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-15-lab/</guid>
      <description>Plan We&amp;rsquo;ll walk around nearby Eisenhower Park and probably Hempstead Plains Preserve. As of Thursday, thunderstorms are 50% likely for class time, so the plan will be to be able to retreat to the van if any significant rain or storm arrives.
Expected conditions Warm, but possibly rainy. Maybe put a raincoat on as your outer layer, and/or toss an umbrella in your bag.
Jobs Following the recorder rotation, Trevor is recording with Nick assisting Nick recorded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mar 08 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-08-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 16:10:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-08-lab/</guid>
      <description>Plan We&amp;rsquo;ll go to Valley Stream State Park. Our focus will continue to be on waterfowl and possible raptors, but also we&amp;rsquo;ll begin spending increasing time looking for perching birds in woods and edge habitats. In addition, we&amp;rsquo;ll try to walk the mile down to Arthur Hendrickson Park to see if the Cackling Goose that has been hanging around there with the Canada Geese flock is around.
Expected conditions It&amp;rsquo;s still going to be cold, so please continue layering up, but we will be in a less-exposed, non-coastal place, partly in the woods, and mostly on pavement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mar 01 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-01-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 10:03:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/mar-01-lab/</guid>
      <description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the Field Trip Instructions and Weekly Checklist Assignment pages yet, please do!
Plan We&amp;rsquo;ll deploy our diving-duck and related waterfowl skills and keep an eye out for winter perching birds and hawks. New hawks for us would include Cooper&amp;rsquo;s Hawk, Sharp-shinned Hawk, and Northern Harrier. We&amp;rsquo;ll start by scanning Jones Bay from the Jones Beach Coast Guard Station. Horned Grebes often peak about now, for instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 22 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-22-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 15:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-22-lab/</guid>
      <description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the Field Trip Instructions page yet, please do!
Plan We&amp;rsquo;re going to focus on using our accumulating waterfowl skills on five varying freshwater bodies around Hempstead Lake State Park.
 We&amp;rsquo;ll plan to start at Smith Pond, a ten-minute drive south of HLSP. We&amp;rsquo;ll scan the pond from the parking lot of Morgan Days Park (What3Words location: vibe.birds.rift; lat/long: 40.659928, -73.653044). ebird hotspot: https://ebird.org/hotspot/L444839. Then we&amp;rsquo;ll move promptly to the state park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 15 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-15-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 11:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-15-lab/</guid>
      <description>Update: the van is apparently repaired, so we&amp;rsquo;re planning to use it. But if anyone prefers to travel to the first site on your own—Google Maps locations are below—and meet us there without coming to Hofstra, please contact me about that.
Plan  Oyster Bay Marine Center (Sagamore Yacht Club); target species: bay waterfowl, especially the rare in New York Pacific Loon that has been there for almost two weeks, but also Bufflehead, mergansers, scaup, gulls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Checklist Note Assignment</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/weekly-checklist-note-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 10:01:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/weekly-checklist-note-assignment/</guid>
      <description>Each week after lab, unless you are the week&amp;rsquo;s recorder or deputy, your assignment is to post a note on the group checklist (or one of the group&amp;rsquo;s checklists; sometimes there will be more than one). This is due within a week, before the next lab.
Set up (you only need to do this once) Create an eBird account as soon as you can after our first lab. Go to the eBird main page at https://ebird.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 08 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-08-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 11:16:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-08-lab/</guid>
      <description>Remember to bring your completed Field Trip Waiver form. You will need it to attend the lab.
Please sign up for an eBird account soon (see Using eBird), so we can share the lab checklist with you.
Plan We will go to the west end of Jones Beach State Park. Our planned first stop will be for a walk through the dunes and beach at Jones Beach SP&amp;ndash;West End, looking at the dunes, the beach, the ocean, and Jones Inlet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recorder Rotation</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/recorder-rotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 12:17:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/recorder-rotation/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the planned rotation for lab recorders and deputies (see Field Trip Instructions for an explanation and instructions):
   Sequence Recorder Deputy Date     1 Penelope Selina Feb 8   2 Wayne Safiyah Feb 15   3 Nick Sean Feb 22   4 Haley Penelope Mar 1   5 Anthony Wayne Mar 8   6 Trevor Nick Mar 15   7 Chris Haley Mar 29   8 Alex Anthony TBD   9 Selina Trevor TBD   10 Safiyah Chris TBD   11 Sean Alex TBD    (more rows to come!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 01 Lab</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-01-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 13:20:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/feb-01-lab/</guid>
      <description>Plan Introductory presentation in our lab space, Gittleson 323. Then, outdoor walk around Hofstra campus to look for birds for up to 90 minutes. (Not going outside. Severe cold warnings.  )
Special instructions If you have binoculars, please bring them. (If not, no problem.) Dress just to be outside at Hofstra, but warmly because it we will plan to be out for up to 90 minutes, and not always walking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Field Trip Instructions</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/field-trip-instructions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 14:32:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/bio108/posts/field-trip-instructions/</guid>
      <description>We will go on a field trip nearly every Friday morning at 8. Usually we will ride in the van to one or two destinations less than 30 minutes from Hofstra. We will normally return by 11 AM. Very occasionally, we might cut into class time, which immediately follows.
Preparations in advance  We will need your signed/filled-in permission form before you can go on any trips off campus. Seriously, plan to be able to dress—just a few times—for very cold conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>